Vijay K

22 years | +91-8220520961

Profile Summary

Goal oriented Sales Professional with 1.3 years of experience in Sales domain working across Automobile and Life Insurance sectors with proven ability in Field sales, lead generation and Product advisory endowed with exceptional interpersonal skills.

Professional Experience

SSB TATA Motors, Tanjavur

Sales Advisor

June 2016 to April 2017

- Successfully met monthly and quarterly targets and generated revenue worth Rs. 50 lakh
- Maintained strong and extensive knowledge of all vehicle features, makes, models and inventory in order to consistently provide the best customer service
- Understood the requirements of the customer and suggested cars according to their needs
- Key member of Product Demonstration team responsible for client conversion post test drive
- Explaining the operating features, warranties, paper work of cars to the customer
- Provided financial advice, communicated with sales managers and finance managers in order to close deals and maintain loyal customer base
- Responsible for lead generation through business collaborations with Banks and Insurance companies
- Resolved customer queries regarding the automobiles & associated services on time
- Responsible for collecting after sales feedback and informed the respective departments the same

KOTAK Life Insurance, Tiruvarur

Field Sales

July 2017 to November 2017

- Analyzed the specific needs of the customer via careful surveys to develop data driven sales pitches
- Assess the client's financial status, spot problem areas and offer solutions to rectify them
- Seek out new clients and develop networking to find new customers and generate lists of prospective clients
- Assisted customers with sales needs with a strong emphasis on customer service and salesmanship
- Developed and maintained loyal client database to increase sales volume

HDFC Field Sales September 2018 to March 2019

- Understood the requirements of the customer and suggested loans according to their needs
- Provided financial advice, communicated with sales managers and finance managers in order to close deals and maintain loyal customer base
- Seek out new clients and develop networking to find new customers and generate lists of prospective clients
- Successfully completed all the monthly targets with additional business of 40%

Academic Qualifications

Degree	Year	Institute, University/ Board	Percentage
B.Com (Marketing)	2016	A.V.V.M.Sri.Pushpam College Poondi, Thanjavur	53.20
H.S.C	2013	National Higher Secondary School, Mannargudi	55
S.S.C.	2011	Ashoka Sishu Vihar Matriculation School, Mannargudi	57

Skill Set

- Complete understanding of automobile sales
- Effective knowledge over sales of financial instruments such as insurance
- Optimistic communication skills
- Ability to drive sales through innovative ideas
- Smart team player

Other Achievements

- Finished Entrepreneur Development Cell Skill Course Certified by Ministry of Science and Technology NSTEDB, Govt of India, New Delhi
- Participated in Special Camping Program organized by National Service Scheme Bharathidasan University
- Student coordinator for the inter college cultural competition "Pushpamala"

Interests and Hobbies

- Singing Carnatic music
- Playing cricket
- Playing Badminton

Personal Details

• Name : Vijay.K

Father's Name : Keerthivasan.S
 Mother's Name : Rajeswari.K
 Date of Birth : 14-01-1996
 Gender : Male

Nationality : Indian
Marital status : Single

Address : No:24/41, East Second Street

Mannargudi, Thiruvarur(DT)- 614001

• Email ID : vijayram731@gmail.com

Contact No : +91-8220520961

Declaration:

I declare that the above facts given by me are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

(Vijay.K)